Guilherme Morone Araujo

guimorone@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/guimorone

https://guimorone.github.io

Summary

Originally from Rio but now based in Recife, I've had the privilege of growing up in two vibrant cities. My passions are as diverse as my background, ranging from an avid love for games and books to an insatiable curiosity for travel and technology. Furthermore, I am always eager to explore new opportunities and challenges that can help me grow both as a professional and as a person, fueled by my passion for learning and applying new technologies to solve real-world problems.

I have been working on Software Development since 2022. Not only that, but I am used to developing Big Data applications that demand high efficiency, scalability, and low cost. All my projects demanded skills in web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing, in order to deliver quality solutions to clients.

Through these experiences, I have gained multiple certifications, such as The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp and Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and Al in Google Cloud - Locales. I am fluent in Portuguese and have a solid proficiency in English.

Experience



Student Teaching Assistant

Centro de Informática UFPE

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Student Teaching Assistant in the discipline of Software and Systems Engineering for Computer Engineering.



Junior Software Enginner I

Oncase

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023 (3 months)

- · Developed Big Data applications with a focus on high efficiency, scalability, and low cost.
- Developed frontend applications using React (JavaScript, TypeScript and HTML/CSS) and Redux.
- Implemented backend functionality using Python frameworks Flask and Django.
- Implemented effective CI/CD pipelines for seamless integration and deployment through Docker and GitHub Actions.
- In general, utilized skills in web development (Django, React and HTML/CSS), data engineering, CI/ CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Enhanced customer relationships through the delivery of top-notch solutions.
- Ensured high-quality and scalable application development.
- Hosted applications on Google Cloud Platform using Cloud Run and Artifact Registry.
- Utilized Amazon Web Services for hosting, leveraging services like Amplify, Route53, and Lambda.



Software Engineer Trainee II

Oncase

Jan 2023 - Oct 2023 (10 months)

Developed Big Data applications that demanded high efficiency and scalability, as well as low cost. Main skills used: Web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions and cloud computing.



Software Engineer Trainee I

Oncase

Aug 2022 - Jan 2023 (6 months)

I developed applications that demanded high efficiency and scalability, as well as low cost. Main skills used: Web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions and cloud computing.



Mobile Engineer

InSpace

Aug 2022 - Oct 2022 (3 months)

Identification of objects (censored specificity) from a mobile camera for legal purposes.



FullStack Engineer Intern

Oncase

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022 (7 months)

As a full-stack developer, I worked building web applications using Flask (Python) and ReactJS.



Game Developer

S.C.A Technology Ltda

Jun 2021 - Oct 2021 (5 months)

I have worked on web apps (educational simulators) using Construct 3 software and JavaScript mainly.



Game Developer

S.C.A Technology Ltda

May 2020 - Dec 2020 (8 months)

I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

Education



👸 Universidade Federal de Pernambuco

Bachelor, Computer Engineering 2019 - 2024

Licenses & Certifications



The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp - Udemy

- Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and Al in Google Cloud -Locales - Google Cloud Skills Boost 3311200
- Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Networking Google Cloud Skills Boost 3305980
- Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Infrastructure in Google Cloud Locales Google Cloud Skills Boost 3303084
- Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud Computing Fundamentals -Locales - Google Cloud Skills Boost 3302433

Skills

Django • React.js • TypeScript • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) • Cloud Computing • Web Development • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • C++ • Git